So, I've spent this whole time talking
about both session storage and local
storage. And you may wonder why
um show you how to use both when they
seem to be doing the same thing. What it
does lets you persist data even when you
reload the page. Well, there are some
slight differences and that's what I'm
going to talk about in this video. Um
so, if you come over here to the
application uh tab, you can see that
I've got a key that says hello and a
value that says world. Um and that's in
session storage. And in local storage
you can see I have got my data with um
that array inside of it which is great.
Okay so that data is stored in local
storage and that data is stored in
session storage. If I open up another
tab and I go back to Oh, sorry.
All right. Well, sorry it took forever
to open the other tab, but if I go to a
new tab that is open to the exact same
website address, um, you can see that my
local storage is still there. But when I
go to my session storage, it's actually
gone. So on this one, I've got both
items in my session storage. And in this
one, I've only got one. Um, and over
here in local uh in local storage, you
can see I've got the key and the value.
Over here in local storage, you can see
that key and value exists. And that is
the difference between local storage and
session storage. Session storage lives
within the tab. So when I close the tab,
it's gone. Local storage lives basically
forever. It lives until either you
delete it or someone else comes along
and programmatically deletes it. Um, but
you may wonder, is this a security flaw?
Well, um, local storage, if you notice
how it's stored, it's stored in
http/lohost
5500. What that means is that this data
is only available if you are on the
website httplohost
on port 5500.
If you were not, you would not be able
to access this. So local storage will
live pretty much indefinitely until you
clear it. Session storage will live
until you close the tab. And it cannot
be visible across tabs. So, I could open
a new tab here and go again to localhost
5500 and I would be able to access all
of the local storage, but I would not be
able to access any of the session
storage between either of those two
tabs.